[Music]
color
present color
[Music]
h
good evening please be seated
let me tell you something about the
young folks we just met that was the
John Marshall High School Air Force
Junior
Roc its mission is to develop citizens
of character dedicated to serving their
nation and community that unit was open
in 2010 that has influenced young
citizens in leadership discipline and
service by the way Bruce who you saw
there is the pipe major of the Irish
American Club East Side pipe band has
been playing the pipe since he was 12 12
years old can we get one more round of
applause please
[Music]
please let's listen to I'm gonna take
Dan Hansen with me everywhere I go how's
that once again good evening everybody
my name is Russ Mitchell I'm with WKYC
channel 3 I'm the 6 and 11:00 anchor it
is a pleasure to be with you tonight I
want to thank the Hansen Dan and Debbie
for inviting me to be a part of this Dan
and Debbie were some of my first friends
when I moved to Cleveland 12 years ago
and it's an honor to know them can we
get the first round of applause of the
evening for The Hansons please who do
amazing
job let me tell you a bit about the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame it
was started back in
2010 this is the largest annual
Gathering of ethnic Community leaders in
Cleveland attendees represent 65
different ethnic Heritage each year
about a 100 worthy nominations are
submitted and previous inductees give
their input and a committee finally
narrows it down to six outstanding
people the main criteria for
introduction is to have made a
significant and Lasting contribution to
one or more ethnic groups or to the
ethnic diversity of the city as a
whole and once again this is an great
event every year the Hanson's put it on
and it's always very successful and
tonight of course will be no exception
to that
want to introduce some folks uh in the
room I have been asked to point out one
of them city council president Blain
Griffin president Griffin are you
there Lan
Griffin
the the 2014 graduate of the leadership
Cleveland class best class
ever I believe bla thank you very much
say a few words
thank you Russ good evening good evening
come on you guys could do better than
that good evening good evening if you
seen how beautiful and how great you
look and how you represent Cleveland you
will see why I'm ecstatic and why I'm
happy to be here today I first want to
thank Dan and Deb let's get them a round
of applause for really growing up with
this
[Applause]
together Cleveland is known for our
diversity and our ethnic communities and
no matter which of the 20 backgrounds
that you come from in the city of
Cleveland we all come together uh to be
Cleveland strong and Cleveland proud I
do want to thank all of the honores and
congratulate all of the honores uh but
before I do that I want to welcome the
Ambassador for Estonia if he could
please stand the Ambassador for
[Music]
Estonia and I didn't want to mess this
up but I believe it's uh John prick did
I say that right got it then we also
have the Ambassador for Ireland that is
here if we can recognize
[Music]
her and I'll save our ambassador for
last but I will give kudos to all of the
uh congrats to all of the winners
especially my good friend my sister once
a council person always a council person
uh councilwoman don't Dona Brady where's
Dona Brady
[Music]
at Dona we miss you and I might just try
to come back and find a way to try to
put you back on the team somewhere but
anyway donor Brady thank you and Dan her
husband as well as here former
councilman and state senator I also want
to make sure that I acknowledge Veronica
dolberg who has done so much great work
of shica police stand
[Music]
Veronica one of my favorite people in
the world I know he's not with us
anymore his daughter Jo is here but Dr
Eugene Jordan who helped raised a lot of
us want to make sure we give him a round
of
applause Erica pusar from the uh
Estonian Community want to acknowledge
you and thank you as
well Johnny Woo everybody knows Johnny
Woo one of the best movie Producers but
more so just a strong Clevelander if
Johnny woer please stand
and last but not least me and this
gentleman had an opportunity to travel
Air Lingus together over to Ireland and
it was hard to believe but this man
might be more popular in Ireland than he
is actually in Cleveland but Ambassador
Eddie Crawford if he could please stand
[Applause]
here ladies and gentlemen this is
Cleveland this is Cleveland you'll hear
from my colleague Mike peni and my other
colleague Jasmine Santana is here we
love this city we love its diversity we
love all of this coming together and
once again we' like to thank you all for
being here at the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame thanks Dan
thanks Deb you guys have a great
[Music]
evening Mr President thank you we'd also
like to acknowledge City community
relations director Angela sh
Woodson mayor bib is in tonight a round
of applause please for director Shu
Woody
[Applause]
hi good to see
you good evening
everyone in the abson of Mayor Justin
bib first we want to thank Deb Dan and
the Cleveland people.com for just this
effort that they work tirelessly to put
on year after year in addition we also
want to con congratulate and continue to
uplift the past awardees and the current
awardees of our city mayor bib does give
his deepest regrets for not being here
today but we just want we're just so
happy and I'm happy to be here as a
community relations director because
this is the richness of
Cleveland today's richness showcases
120 different ethnic groups throughout
the city and we get to uplift the
leadership and the significance
contribution and endurance ing uh
efforts that each of you have done in
all of the awardees today this is what
is unique about Cleveland if you could
see this room from where I stand this is
Cleveland and it's proud to host you
here by the River today so again as we
stand with you we congratulate all the
honores the council president
acknowledged everybody how proud We Are
of you and your efforts and the
continuing work you do to provide Unity
peace and Mutual understanding in our
city thank
[Applause]
[Music]
you director thank
you representing the office of the
kayaga county executive is Christopher
Alvarado the director of regional
collaboration Christopher you here there
he is Round of Applause please for
[Applause]
Christopher so yes as you can tell I am
not uh Chris Ronan uh and I'm always
grateful to come in after uh council
president Griffin because he always
makees sure to acknowledge everybody and
I don't have to remember every single
one of our uh honores uh but we're
grateful uh that you're all here uh this
evening I'm Chris Alvarado the director
of regional collaboration for kyoga
County Executive Chris Rona executive
rain is deeply apologetic that he is not
able to be here and he sends his deepest
regards he really wanted to be here
tonight to celebrate this all all of you
especially given the opening of The
Welcome Center uh here in the city of
Cleveland uh this year and his personal
commitment to making Cleveland kaga
County and Northeast Ohio a place of
welcome for everybody on his behalf it's
an honor to be here tonight among
distinguished guests and honores from
our local community and from around the
world the CLE
International Hall of Fame since 2010
has represented the Pinnacle of
Excellence guiding the culture of
openness and
caring that our shared home is
recognized for tonight we're honoring
those who have demonstrated
extraordinary leadership Innovation and
dedication to their fields and who have
profoundly impacted our diverse and
Vibrant Community kayaga county is home
to more than 120 unique cult cultures
and nationalities from all corners of
the world it's a reminder that at our
core we are a land of immigrants and our
diversity is our strength this diversity
brings Dynamic energy and a variety of
perspectives that enriches our community
and all of Northeast Ohio let us also
take a moment to recognize the
importance of unity and collaboration in
our increasingly interconnected World by
embracing diversity and Foster during
International cooperation we can
overcome challenges and create a
brighter future for generations to come
I on behalf of County Executive Ronan
extend my warmest congratulations to
each of the honores tonight your passion
vision and unwavering commitment
inspires each of us thank you for your
outstanding contributions to our shared
Global Community please enjoy the
evening and let us continue to celebrate
the power of diversity excellence and
achievement together thank
you Christopher thank you now let's
please welcome to the podium one of our
hosts for the evening the co-founder of
the Cleveland International Hall of Fame
Mr Dan
Hansen well hi everybody I'm gonna
try to it sounds a little muddy to me
maybe that's my aging ears but uh too
many years playing guitar but I'm going
to try to talk really loud and clear and
I appreciate your attention because I
have a lot of people to thank you know
this is another sellout as you can see
um and as people have mentioned
Cleveland Northeast Ohio is home to
people of 120 different ethnic heritages
we have about 75 of those represented
tonight but even cooler is there's a a
group that have were born somewhere else
or came in from somewhere else and are
here tonight and I just want to I just
kind of did it uh off the cuff here
because I wanted to read it because it's
pretty impressive so if you hear your
nationality or if you're that person
feel free to you know woohoo or whatever
so we have people here from
Albania
Armenia
China
Colombia the Czech
Republic Dominican
Republic
[Applause]
Estonia
Ethiopia
Finland
France
[Music]
Greece
Hungary
India
Ireland
Italy lvia
Lebanon
Lithuania
Mexico
Nigeria
Poland Puerto
Rico
Serbia
Slovakia
Slovenia
Switzerland
Syria the
Philippines turkey
Ukraine and Vietnam and there may be
some others so that's pretty impressive
you know years ago whether you call him
mayor Senator or Governor voyavich he
said people who Embrace their ethnic
Heritage turn out to be great Americans
because it's it's important to keep
those traditions and food and music and
faith and all and that ethnic diversity
is part of what makes Cleveland so great
the six and duct these tonight are what
makes Cleveland so great too and I wish
I had time to tell stories about each of
them if I had time I would tell about
Dona Brady and watching her work so hard
to get a sister city relationship with
Fier Albania or to get that Beautiful
Albanian cultural Garden started and how
she tells everyone who will listen and
even if they won't listen then Mother
Teresa was Albanian right
I tell about that day when she invited
the president of Albania and he came in
and it was probably the worst weather
Cleveland ever had but we had the
dedication of that garden and that was
donut if I had time I'd tell you about
Ambassador Ed Crawford who you know the
Irish Cultural Garden was dedicated in
1939 and it had some well Decades of
neglect really it it really didn't have
what it should and one day Ambassador
Crawford I would tell tell you was
driving by and being a man of action he
did something and he did a lot and he
started the Irish Garden Club and now
it's one of the Premier uh cultural
Gardens and i' tell you about the day
when he invited the t-shock of Ireland
now the t-shock is like the prime
minister right Ambassador that's prime
minister right so the t-shock was here
and the Ambassador and the council
General and Senator voyavich and mayor
Jackson all them and about 200 of
Ambassador Crawford's closest friends
were there that day and he he turned
that around but I don't have time to
tell you that I tell you about Veronica
dalberg creating with her organization
hola a $2 million Hispanic Community
Center in Paynesville it's incredible
but I'd really like to tell
you and I mean this in the best way
Veronica you are a bulldog or a pitbull
you have been fighting for migrants and
immigrants Margaret Wong told us she
she Claws and scratches I remember a
time when there's a family and a man was
going to be deported and he had six kids
and he and his wife were here and the
six kids so Veronica set up a March from
Paynesville to St Casmir Church in
Glenville 83rd swinsky and it was
terrible weather of course and they went
and prayed with Father Eric who's here
and they prayed to the Polish Our Lady
of chest toova and her equivalent Mexico
Our Lady of Guadalupe that's the kind of
Grassroots stuff I'd tell you about uh
Veronica i' tell you about the late Dr
Jordan because he was a walking
Encyclopedia of African-American history
which as he would tell you is really
American history he would talk about the
Emancipation Proclamation Carter G
Woodson the 54th Cavalry which was the
first black Cavalry that fought for free
in the Civil War
um the Tuskegee Airmen the Buffalo
Soldiers all of that but he would tell
us I would tell you this story about
1520 years ago when a small group met at
the African-American Garden there was
Carl Ying there's khed zad and Raj and
some kids from peace in the hood my
sister Debbie and me and Dr Jordan and
Dr Jordan started talking about this
thing that they only knew about in
Oklahoma and Texas and he called it June
and every year he pushed it and pushed
it and pushed it and now obviously
juneth is a Federal holiday and I
personally give a lot of credit to Dr
Jordan for
that I don't have time to tell you all
about Erica pisar either she's uh she
had a rough life no doubt about it she
lived under Soviet occupation in Estonia
she had a flea that she want uh
displaced persons Camp before coming to
America and with her 50 plus years of
teaching us about uh St John's day and
victory day and how would I pronounce
that I'll I'll let the Ambassador tell
you V and Johnny pev always being the
sweetest lady in the room so I mean so I
tell you about all that Eric has done
and finally I tell you about my friend
Johnny Woo who has become one of my best
friends um about 20 years ago Debbie and
I went to Margaret Wong and said who
should we get for an ambassador for the
Chinese community and she said there's
this upand cominging guy named Johnny
Woo you should meet him so we went and
met him and the rest is history he's
he's incredible he with Lisa Wong and V
win started the Cleveland Asian Festival
he along with people like Donna ham
helped create Asia Town out of a crappy
pardon my French
neighborhood um he's the guy who prod
produces one world day and gets us tens
of thousands of people every year so I
have all kinds of stories about Johnny
Woo but I just don't have time cuz I
have to thank some people first person I
have to thank is Russ
Mitchell Russ is a Pros
Pro he was you may not know he was a
national uh anchor for many years and he
came to Cleveland um wanted to slow down
a little he told me and Debbie one day
at lunch you know he's tired of Hustle
bust of New York and Washington DC and
when he got here all of a sudden these
International stories were coming out of
Cleveland Ariel Castro and all this so
he never really got a chance to slow
down but he said he'd be here tonight
even if the Terminal Tower fell and
you're here and we thank you so much
Russ so let's let's here for
Russ city councilman city council
president Blain Griffin's been a
longtime friend uh
back to when he was community relations
director it's a great leader I remember
when he inducted khed in 2016 that was a
great moment here and of course Angela
we go back to C when Jeff Johnson was a
councilman Jeff remember your Glenville
parades and Festival Angela would run
those and we'd work with him and you
know Chris is Chris or's under the
weather but we're glad to have his uh
representative here
can I have your attention please I want
I've got to thank these
people so we have our board members
there John Lewis Mike Miller Juan ly pal
and Debbie Hansen Debbie worked for
about a week to get the parking down to
$3 today from like 10 so she's the one
to thank for the parking of that we have
volunteers Rich kpage R Body Bridget
Moro an John ghost Matt Stafford Michael
horning and there's too many dignitaries
to point out but I have to do a few as
you've heard we have Ireland's
ambassador to the US ambassador n last
year she was on a tour of the Irish
garden with Ambassador Crawford and she
said if he gets inducted into the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame she
would come and do it and she kept her
word and here she is so thank you
Ambassador this is Ambassador Christian
pri's first visit to Cleveland we're so
glad glad he's here maybe you read his
oped in Sunday's plane dealer on
cleveland.com with what's going on with
Russia Ukraine the baltics Poland it's
so important to hear from the Estonian
ambassador of course you'll hear more
from Ambassador Crawford soon but we
have one other we have Ambassador
Heather hajes here uh president of
ccwa and you might not know Ambassador
hajes she was Ambassador to mova and
later Ecuador US ambassador so
Ambassador hajes thank you for being
here we also have the council General
I'm going to ask you again to be quiet I
know it would be a jerk but this is
important stuff these
are we have the council general of
Slovenia here alenka
jerck judges council members all that I
do have to mention our sponsors gold
sponsors and they're in the book you'll
see him on the screen the Irish Garden
Club Kent State University and the
Minutemen family of
companies silver sponsors Albert and
Audrey Ratner you know this is the first
time I think Mr Ratner has missed an
event it's the first night of passover
he couldn't come but he did send a video
keynote and we'll we have links to that
on the website that you can watch it's
about 5 and a half minutes you should
Alex machy
silver sponsors Cleveland Asian Festival
keep May 18th and 19th
together ccwa now 101 years old I
believe Crawford
United Dr Joy Jordan and her family you
know just like her father Dr Joy became
a a worldclass
dentist Eddie KNE where is Eddie
KNE
Eddie okay I have to apologize that he
need you are not in the book as a silver
sponsor I screwed up I had you under
windfall group your company you're not
in the book please everyone a round of
applause for Eddie
KN he's done so much for the uh Chinese
Cultural
Garden Global Cleveland of course Joe
cerman and his team doing amazing things
to open up Cleveland to the world of
welcoming L Anne frangos from the Greek
cultural Garden Margaret Wong and
Associates Margaret of course finest
immigration lawyer in the country and a
great uh great friend of all of us
please ask people
stop all right we need Martin Sweeney
here if you ever one of his events he
holds something up and
says so people can't
hear and I'm just going to wait until
you quiet
down you could talk it in there thank
you very much um Northeast Ohio Regional
sewer district is a silver sponsor we're
thrilled to have our friend Jacqueline
Muhammad here we met her first uh when
she ran African history months at City
Hall she was at the airport it's been a
friend ever since and we love the Sewer
District they're more important than
ever with rain and everything going on
water and they have the best Twitter or
X account ever it's
hilarious dick POG you know the man the
legend uh we could list his
accomplishments
forever and the other the superlative
group is also silver
sponsor now I'm I'm hurrying up here but
this is
important every year we try to get
students here and we always we're glad
to have John Marshall High School do the
color guard
[Music]
but it's expensive so we ask people
every year and you know they want to buy
their own tickets this year we had an
anonymous donor and because of this
person we have five tables of students
here we have students from Benedict and
high
[Applause]
school students from gin
Academy students from some of the Greek
schools I don't think they're here
yet students from Magnificat High
School and students from St Martin the
pores high
school so here's the thing as long as
I'm in trouble anyway um this person did
not want to be recognized but he should
be it's expensive it's a great thing
it's great to have these kids here and I
wouldn't say that it was Ambassador Ed
Crawford but if I were to announce who
this person was who uh was the anonymous
donor I'd probably uh just come out and
say it was Ambassador at Crawford so
thanks for all these students
[Music]
here they're going to be inspired by
tonight's inductees they're going to be
inspired by the past indues and we have
a bunch of them here tonight once again
I'm going to say it real fast but they
deserve to be recognized you'll see them
on the screen later too so when when I
call your name just raise your hand or
stand these are some of the previous
indues who are here Anda cook Anthony
Yen August po Carl Robeson Carolyn
bog dick po Dr W Curry georan Willow
Jerry
quinnn yawa
Ryan ingr bublis Irene Maro
Jenny
Brown Jim
CR Joe
Meisner Jose
Feliciano Ken
Kovach Margaret Lynch Margaret
Wong Maria
Pana Mary Rose
Oar Michael
penic Paul
Burick Pierre
bani Ralph perk Jr
the Reverend Otis Moss Jr Sheila Murphy
Crawford Sudan
sat and Valerie McCall so they've all
been p and duties let's give them a
round of
applause now finally if Carl Ying could
come
up Carl where are you this is and then
I'll sit
down kyl where are you there he comes
okay so this this is a Hall of Fame it's
not an annual award show this is for
Lifetime achievements and unfortunately
with a Hall of Fame some of the people
we have to induct prous like Dr Jordan
tonight or some have passed away because
they're
older can you can you grab a water so I
learned so tonight we're going to
recognize those people who have passed
on either board members or uh inductees
who are no longer with us this a
libation ceremony and you may have heard
about pouring one out for people and all
that but I first learned about it from
Dr Jordan from Carl Ying from khed Samad
people like that who in the
African-American Community who really
show respect for their ancestors and
Elders so along those lines Carl I'd
like to ask for permission from the
elders to continue so thank you so what
we're going to do
there's a Nigerian a Yuba term Yuba
people come from Nigeria Ben in Togo
called as and it's kind of like amen
it's kind of like sending Positive Vibes
and an affirmation what we're going to
do I'm going to announce the name of the
person who has passed on Carl is going
to pour a little out and you're all
going to say a after the name so let's
try it once a a okay so we're going to
remember those who have gone before us
sister Alicia Alvarado
a Dr Mohan bafna a Margaret
Kender a bill
Carney Arie de laort
a Dr du thck do a via Elman
Richard flushman I Richard gamon I
Robert H
A Patricia Hansen a Joseph holer a sh
Donna ham a jack kale a Helen
carpens a Lonnie mcau a Ernie m
a Sam Miller a William Miller a Steve
Malloy a n panika a mayor Ralph perk a
Tony
Picos Bishop Edward pvic a judge Ray
Panka Bishop Anthony
pillar Vladimir Roose a Thomas
scanlin Paul Sharia a Bert Seymour a
paramjit sing a luri stoa a Tara
sagala Senator George voyavich
and Leo
wethal so I sincerely apologize if I
missed anyone we will never forget them
we'll never forget them to everyone else
please stay healthy we don't want to add
on to this list thank you Carl I'll turn
it over to Russ I'm sorry for it's going
so long
thanks Dan thank you very much and by
the way the Terminal Tower did not fall
I'm happy to report
them if I can please have your attention
for just a couple more minutes before we
let you begin your dinner in peace we'll
take a little break and then we'll start
our program we now would like to have
the
invocation I'd like to invite to the
podium father Eric
orac father Eric is pastor at both the
shrine church at St sanl and Slavic
Village St Casmir Church in Glenville he
is also National vice president of the
Polish American priest Association and
was its former president father Eric
good
evening to you good even you as well
toughest job on the dis being the last
person between people in their dinner so
we have to make it worth your while for
those who couldn't resist and already
ate your salad and maybe even dipped
into that cheesecake in front of you the
blessings
retroactive and for everything else that
comes just today we're doing a special
no
calories good and gracious God
it is with joy filled and thankful
hearts that we gather together this
evening to honor Excellence within our
midst in tonight's inductees into the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame
throughout the years those who have
Blaze the trail of coming to our area to
establish a new and better life have
encountered many trials along the way
but our inductees this evening show us
how at any time obstacles can be become
achievements how perseverance does
indeed pay off and how the richness of
our diversity properly respected and
celebrated blossoms into the unity that
we now share we ask your Bountiful
Blessing Lord to come upon this food and
fellowship of which we shall partake and
upon all those who have worked so hard
to make this day and its events possible
we ask your blessings too upon all
gathered here upon our distinguished
guests and our induct the May our
celebration this day refresh our spirits
and fill us with renewed hope may it
enliven us to embrace the work yet to be
accomplished for the greater good may we
be instruments to inspire many
especially the young to embrace their
Heritage share it with pride and yet be
open to the richness that comes to them
through Others May Your Divine
assistance accompany us this day and
always amen
and as we say in Polish Smo which is
like Bona Petit only
better father thank you please enjoy
your dinner we'll resume our program in
just a few
[Music]
moments e
a e
[Music]
can we please get a round of applause
for Mr Bruce Greg it's
fantastic and if we could have everyone
back in their seats we would like to
resume our program now it's time to
induct some folks into the international
Hall of Fame also want to thank and give
a big round of applause to the amazing
folks who prepared this food tonight and
served it to us as well come we get a
round of applause for them
[Applause]
all right are we ready to induct some
people into the international Hall of
Fame I tell you I'm taking Dan with me
everywhere I go are we ready folks to
induct some people into the
international Hall of
[Applause]
Fame want to let you know that besides
the award very nice award that they will
receive tonight they'll also get a Hall
of Fame lapel pin also there going to be
proclamations from several folks
tonight they include Governor Mike dwine
Cleveland Mayor Justin
bib Cleveland City Council president bla
Griffin Ohio State House of
Representatives Tom Patton Congressman
Dave Joyce and others as well all right
let me get your attention please because
the time is here to to induct some
really good folks into the Cleveland
International Hall of
Fame all right our first inductee
tonight important stuff here folks our
first inductee tonight is councilwoman
donor
Brady she will be
introduced by councilman Mike penc let
me tell you something about councilman
fenic I'm sure you know Ward a
councilman the dean of the city council
who served the neighborhood of Northeast
Ohio since
1978 making him the longest serving
council member in the city's history he
was inducted himself into the Hall of
Fame last year and he is on television
in Cleveland more than I am councilman
Mike
won thank you Russ can everybody hear me
I hope now I've been reminded since I'm
the first batter up here to remind all
the future presenters as it pertains to
their time limit because if you remember
last year we were here for 3 and 1/2
hours and um and I was the last
recipient so at that time half the
audience had left and the other half and
had too much to drink at that point okay
so we don't want to find ourselves in
that situation again um let me just say
this and again I want to thank everyone
who came out tonight to fill this
beautiful Ballroom for this wonderful
event I'd like to acknowledge and
welcome our the clergy that is Here
Local elected public officials who are
here tonight along with the ambassadors
Council generals and honorary Council
generals who represent their countries
and cultures as well as the loved ones
and Friends of our honores if you cannot
hear me raise your hand in the back I
would like to congratulate all the
honores to be inducted this evening into
the inter Cleveland International Hall
of Fame I'd like to thank the nominating
committee who worked diligently to seek
out those who've contributed Ed greatly
to Cleveland's Rich ethnic racial and
religious
diversity those of us who've been
inducted in the past can attest to what
a great honor this is and I wish to
thank Debbie and Dan Hansen for their
ongoing commitment in keeping this
tradition alive and I want to say that
again thank you Debbie and
P um I have been honored and been asked
to introduce my longtime friend Dona
Brady who wears her Albanian Heritage as
as a proud Badge of Courage I've known
Dona a long time from being the old
school Democratic activist within our
party to holding elected public office
in Cleveland City Council serving from
December 1999 through February 2020 in
three distinct WS districts in
Cleveland's West Side I've always Amed
her tenacity
but also her compassion my brothers and
sisters in dealing with neighborhood
related issues I heard her say often at
the table when speaking on behalf of the
community she would say I'm here
representing my
constituents my
constituents I learned that firsthand in
2000 when I was council president and we
were going through the redistricting
process which we're about to go through
again when she was concerned about
making sure her Ward was was left intact
I learned that you never want to upset
an Albanian who was also part Italian
okay remember
that when the opportunity presented
itself to have the Albanian community
and culture represented in historic
cultural Gardens Dona was right there I
always commended her for her drive to
ensure that Not only was the garden done
right but also that it became a tribute
to the life's work of Saint Mother
Teresa who was born in in Albania and
heard to call from God to become a
missionary to serve the poor I that's
[Music]
right I know Donna listen up I know
Donna took her inspiration from Mother
Teresa in her Devotion to family and
community and in her way of inspiring
others to work together for the greater
good please listen to this St Mother
Teresa want said do not allow yourself
to be disen heartened by any failure as
long as you have done your best I know
Dona Brady always did her best it is my
honor to introduce Dona Brady as our
newest member of the Cleland National
Hall of Fame come on up
lady where are you hiding come on up
[Applause]
on it's all thank you so
much
oh oh boy thank you so much uh Michael
um it was my pleasure working with you
for all those years and uh I really
enjoyed Cleveland City Council I really
did well good evening I am truly honored
to be inducted into the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame class of
[Music]
2024 and I congratulate my fellow
nominees or inductees shall I
say I'd like to thank claya spirollari
over there for submitting my nomination
and the entire Albanian Community for
supporting me and thank you for being
here with me me this evening they're
over
there I'd also like to thank Dan and
Debbie Hansen for their outstanding
coverage of the many Albanian
events after the fall of Communism in
Albania 30 years ago I had the pleasure
of getting to know and working with the
new Albanian immigrants and subsequently
with the Kos ofar Albanian
refugees who were sent to Cleveland
after the
war I'd like to give a shout out to
Sister Kathleen Ryan over there because
her dedication in assisting the kosovars
was so tremendous they arrived here with
literally nothing but the shirts on
their backs
since then thousands of albanians have
migrated to Greater
Cleveland they quickly learned the
language took jobs they could find in
order to support their
families and became certified in their
former professions or new professions
and many of them started up their own
businesses I am so proud of the Albanian
people I have observed their commitment
to family and the importance they place
on hard work and
education I watched as they made their
own way and succeeded in their new
country
5,000 miles from
home my husband Dan and I tour Albania
[Music]
extensively Albania is spectacularly
beautiful with mountains and
valleys and clean lakes and streams
located on the clear blue Adriatic
Sea the people are generous they're
friendly and they're
helpful and the food is
fantastic I can't wait to go
back it's hard to believe that we are
now experiencing our third generation of
albanians here in Northern
Ohio and I feel very fortunate to be
part of their
family working with this amazing
Community has been one of the most
fun and you know that you guys are
fun the most fun interesting and
rewarding experience of my life thank
you
again
fere this is for you
councilwoman once again congratulations
to
you our next inductee into the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame is Ambassador
Ed
[Applause]
Crawford he will be introduced by
Ireland's ambassador to the United
States Geraldine burn
n before the Ambassador came to
Washington she spent 5 years as
Ireland's ambassador to the UN most
recently during Ireland's term serving
on the security Council as an elected
member please welcome to the podium
Ambassador Geraldine
per good evening everyone
to to
honor mask in my own national language
um it's a great great pleasure to be
with you here this evening I came here
um for the last time in November when I
had the honor to open uh officially open
the office of Ireland's First honory
Council the amazing Mark uh Owens who's
with us this evening uh we did that last
November and Mark is doing a tremendous
job
here tonight is a particular Delight for
me when I meet Ambassador Edward
Crawford we usually speak about many
topics uh occasionally GE
politics uh often Irish culture and even
this evening Irish
poetry it's clear that Edward has a an
extraordinary breath of experience both
at home here and in
Ireland he's committed to preserving and
fostering Irish Roots his own Irish
roots and the absolutely exceptional
Irish Garden at the Cleveland culture
Gardens really is a great Testament to
that in
Ireland Edward Crawford is known as a
proud Irish American and an honorable
ambassador of the United States to
Ireland in truth we didn't so much
welcome you back home to your Homeland
Edward as we like to think that in many
ways you never
left when Ambassador Crawford presented
his credentials to to Ireland's
President Michael D Higgins in July 2019
he and his wife Mary began a term in
Ireland that would coincide with one of
the most challenging periods for all of
us across the globe Ambassador Crawford
was in Ireland During the period of the
covid-19 pandemic and that he was in
Ireland and supported not just the US
Embassy but US citizens right across
Ireland during that time is such a
powerful ful illustration of his
commitment to public service but before
the pandemic I know uh that Mary and
Edward had a chance to connect with
their Irish roots to experience that CAD
mea fulta the 100,000 welcomes that we
in Ireland like to speak of and there
are especially fond memories of you both
in a small village called boher Brie in
North cork where Ambassador Crawford's
mother Katherine Healey
hailed from and to which I understand
Ambassador you took your first official
visit now I was told that when you got
to the village in Cork that you were
presented with the boher bu GAA Gaelic
Athletic Association Jersey I'm a bit
surprised you're not sporting it this
evening but I promise that that secret
will remain safe with
me I believe that Katherine Healey left
boher Brie in 1927 and aged just 16 to
come to the United States and her story
and that of the ambassador's family
forms part of that great Patchwork of
generations of Irish who left Ireland um
for Better Lives looking to find Better
Lives for themselves and their families
in the US we like to say that the great
tapestry of the United States is woven
through with the green of the emerald
aisle
many of those untold
stories are of young
women young women like the ambassador's
mother who took incredible risk and
sacrifice to seize opportunity I imagine
that the ambassador's mother leaving
Ireland during a period of profound
change could never in a million years
have imagined that her son would return
to Ireland as the ambassador of the
United States
indeed I think it might actually have
been a great surprise to her to your mom
that the Next Generation would actively
seek to return to an island that she had
been forced to leave as our great woman
poet I believe our greatest woman poet
Ian Boland put it in her poem that's
entitled The Immigrant Irish she
said what they survive D we could not
even live by their lights now it's time
to imagine how they stood there what
they stood with that their possessions
may become our power we're incredibly
fortunate in this Century in the century
since many journeyed to the United
States that Ireland has prospered and is
indeed the country that our diaspora
want to come to today I've seen so much
here in Cleveland of what must have
drawn that young Catherine Healey to
this uh State almost 100 years ago it's
a great Irish American Community here
based on history and tradition and also
a 21st century one that's looking
forward there's an openness here and I
will uh conclude soon by saying that one
of the definitions of openness must be
that in a Cleveland a city so associated
with akle and mayo and I know we have
representatives from mayo and AEL
tonight that they've allowed a man like
Edward Crawford with cork Roots uh to
become a member of the international
Hall of
Fame we know that the great connection
with Cleveland is even more tangible now
we have a direct flight and a Lingus
Flight that Ambassador Crawford and his
wife were um happy to be on going to
Ireland and which will fly all of you
who are willing to line up back to
Ireland as soon as you can get a ticket
uh back to Dublin it's my great honor
tonight to induct a proud Irish American
ambassador Edward Crawford into the
Cleveland International Hall of
Fame and as he comes to the stage I'd
like to say it's an honor that pays
tribute to him to his family I will say
in particular to Katherine Healey and to
his own great commitment to public
service on behalf of the United States
Ambassador Crawford
I'll make things short and
sweet you know number
one I'm very very excited to be here
with my fellow graduates of this
class I already know where the top class
in the last 10 or 15 years and we're
going to do better in the
future but I want to come back and
follow on a a comment from Mr uh Griffin
when he talked about
Cleveland and the Ambassador thank you
very much for coming all the way to be
here tonight you know uh you're special
Cleveland's special my family special
and you now you mention my mother so I'm
I'm forced to have to tell a story to
everyone about my
mom you know because we are Irish and uh
we're proud of that and the families are
important to us and everyone in this
room that are part of their families
it's important to be there it's
important to have that cality and that
warmth that you have between you know
families boys Sons relatives so let me
and if you're going to be a real average
friend you have to be a good Storyteller
so I want to tell you a quick story I
think you're going to love it it tells
all about who I am what we are what the
Irish are it's very simply Kathleen
Healey that the Ambassador spoke about
my mother left Ireland when she was 177
years old she came to America Now The
Story
begins simply we were living in New York
City in
1948 in all the apartment buildings in
in a part of New York City I hated my
Mom hated it was noise it was everything
else and my mom decided she was going to
take her two boys her two
boys now I'm going to have to make three
boys cuz my old older brother was a
little part of the problem but it was
with my older brother you know how this
goes in an Irish family but the three of
us and my mother and father the next
thing I knew I was in a truck my father
was an
electrician I got into the truck my with
my two brothers in the back we had
sleeping bags and we started down the
New Jersey 10
Turnpike we got to the Pennsylvania
Turnpike when we got to what we thought
was going to be the Ohio Turnpike there
was no
turnpike I said oops you know in the
back we got out of the thing we were
thought we we're on the way to
California so this is exciting this is
my mom and she's she's all fired up
about it my dad's just driving along and
so forth so we get the the Ohio line and
we got go north not this is important
but it is important we went North to a
little town called Cony at Ohio where
it's for the first time we ever stopped
in Ohio here we are in this little town
we go they had a back a little pool in
the back we took showers and so forth it
was very exciting so we get up in the
morning this
is
1948 it's June it's June 16th or 17th I
don't know exactly was a Sunday we get
in the truck we Pile oursel in we get
all our clothes and everything and away
we're go we're going through Chicago
we're going to California where the gold
is this is my
mom and right in the middle of downtown
in Superior right there 28th in Superior
something happened
boom
boom that was the engine of the
truck that was our end of our trip to
California and I grew up in Cleveland
it's been a wonderful and Mr Griffin
it's a great place and when you have
people
like Albert racken and this gentleman
right over here he's been acknowledged
I'll do it again and again and again
my can I use your name
[Music]
again I'll say it again Jim Mr
Ranken okay that's it that's my story
I'm going to stick to it thank you for
being here have a nice day
Ambassador Crawford
congratulations our next honor tonight
another amazing Community leader
Veronica
dolberg she will be introduced by
Cleveland councilwoman Jasmine
Santana councilwoman Santana was the
first Latina council member in the
city's history she is the first Latina
council member in the city's history
councilwoman Santana represents Clark
Fulton stockyards in portions of
Brooklyn Center and Tremont
neighborhoods she's also the council's
representative to the City's community
relations board please welcome to the
podium Cleveland Council woman Jasmine
San good to see you
weno
di good evening everyone once again
councilwoman Jasmine Santana
representing W 14 I am incredibly proud
as a Latina to stand before you today to
celebrate the outstanding achievement of
the incredible Latina Veronica
dalberg I've had the privilege of
working with the same Community with
Veronica since 2006 through my work at
Metro Health Veronica and I originally
bonded over the importance of healthc
care access across cultures but through
the many years together we've had the
opportunity to work together on a wide
range of cultural and language access
issues throughout our collaboration she
has consistently demonstrated passion
and focus on advocating for the Latino
immigrants in our
community whether the issue was facing
our that was facing our community like
housing and stability or the importance
of legal rights that affect hundreds and
thousands of our immigrant communities
or Child Care Veronica has spent her
life advocating for people who are
limited and their ability to advocate
for themselves Veronica's commitment to
Excellence has not only brought honor to
ourselves but created opportunities for
people who live in the shadows of our
community I'm incredibly proud and
grateful to know Veronica delberg and
present her award today and proud to
work with her and have her in the city
of Cleveland Veronica your achievements
as a are a shining example of what we
can we could accomplish with dedication
and advocacy within our community
congratulations on your outstanding
success and your induction today we are
so very proud of you and to have you in
our community thank you for your passion
and commitment to the Immigrant
community
[Music]
[Applause]
than
you sorry I'm a little
nervous um thank you so very much this
is um a huge honor I'm deeply deeply
honored to get this award I want to
thank Dan and Hansen for this incredible
event just to see so many people
together to celebrate diverse cultures
ethnicities languages it truly fills me
with
optimism especially you know I feel that
it's a strong um just a powerful
contradiction to the narrative that we
might see on social media or TV about
immigrants um this is just so positive
and uplifting so thank you um
everybody's talking about their mom and
I follow uh Eddie and who I want to say
hi to and honor as well um I want to
tell a little bit a story about my
parents who were both immigrants my
father was born and raised in Hungary
and he had to flee Hungary and lived in
a refugee camp as a displaced person in
Austria and then from there he took an
immigrant ship to Venezuela and became a
Venezuelan immigrant and a Venezuelan
citizen I should say and he learned to
speak Spanish which he spoke with a very
thick Hungarian accent and then he uh
went out went to Mexico where he met my
mom my mom was born and raised in Mexico
in a little small town and um my oldest
brother was born in Mexico but then they
came up to Cleveland because my dad had
some Hungarian friends here in the
Buckeye
neighborhood so my parents lived in a
little apartment there and why this
award feels so improbable to me is
because uh both my parents have passed
away but recently I was going through
some of their letters
because my dad would travel a lot and my
mom would be home in the apartment
pregnant with me not driving not
speaking English not knowing anybody
here and I found this little note in one
of the letters that she sent to my dad
it's from the hospital and it's 3 months
before I was born and it says regarding
obstetrical
reservations I'm afraid your reservation
has been cancelled payment in advance is
the rule in all Cleveland hospitals when
the patient is not covered by Insurance
please contact me at
once I was floored by this my mom could
not have me in Cleveland at the time she
must have felt horrible and I never knew
why I was born in Canton
Ohio so here I am getting the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame award you
know when I wasn't
[Applause]
[Music]
and I can tell you that with all our
organization any Mom Dad worker family
can come to our community center and get
all the help they need free
interpretation free translations access
to Medical Care we help so many people
and I do it really in honor of my
parents and because it's such a
privilege to work with the Immigrant
community and for some visuals we
brought some our folkloric dance leaders
from hanesville
so in closing I would like to just
invite everybody to our Cinco Deo
celebration which will be Saturday May
4th in Paynesville where we celebrate
our I guess our bicultural identity as
Mexicans and Americans we celebrate 4th
of July we celebrate Memorial Day but we
also celebrate our Sinco the Mayo and
our Mexican Independence Day so thank
you so much for allowing us to celebrate
our cultures
[Applause]
M Dober congratulations to
you our next inductee will go in
pous the late dror Eugene Jordan
[Music]
to say some words about Dr Jordan will
be the Reverend Dr Otis Moss Jr what can
be said about Dr Otis Moss Jr I'm going
to try to say a few things here we only
have a few minutes I could spend all
night talking about his
accomplishments of course he was friends
with both Dr Martin Luther King Jr and
Dr Martin Luther King Senor Regional
director Martin Luther King Jr's
Southern Christian leadership conference
leading several campaigns to fight
various forms of discrimination and
segregation he also participated in the
Selma Alabama Civil Rights march with Dr
King and we became close friends with in
1975 he became pastor of the olvet
Institutional Baptist Church which was
then the largest black church in the
state of Ohio he led that church for 33
years before retiring in 2008 ladies and
Gentlemen please welcome to the podium
the Reverend Dr Otis Moss
[Music]
[Applause]
Jr thank you very
kindly and
congratulations to all of the
honores past and present I would like to
take a moment of privilege and ask the
immediate family of Dr Eugene Jordan to
join me here that's the first paragraph
of my
speech if the immediate family Dr Eugene
J would come and join
me briefly tonight
[Applause]
[Music]
and as they
stand each
one is Dr
Jordan Dr Jord two
dentists Dr
John
psychiatrist how
remarkable
indeed how
remarkable Dr Eugene
[Applause]
Jo was a
person a man a leader of
excellence in college in
Ohio in dental school at howood
University but after that and
establishing a
great dental practice practice in this
community he
continued to go to
school he
earned degrees not because he needed
them but because he deserve
them Dr
Jordan has
left an
indelible
Legacy not only for his immediate
family but for all of
us present and
future Dr
John was a Liberation
doctor civil rights
doctor human rights
individual and this
community I dare say this
nation is a better place a greater place
because of his
life and his
work his
life is
now
Immortal because his deeds were so
necessary so
courageous and so
remarkable he deposited so
much not in
himself but in the lives of
others every day of his life we are
better because of you Dr Eugene John and
thanks be to God for your life your
legacy and those who stand now carrying
on the work of greatness if I were at
church I would say Let the Church Say
Amen
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you thank you can you hear me
barely louder yeah normally when there's
so many Jordans together we generally
flip accordingly see who decides what
each other is going to do or we just
listen to Jord and she tells us what
we're going to do um I would like to
thank the um the committee um we are
definitely honored um our community the
African-American Community is honored um
Dad
came um we settled in Cleveland he
University High mom and dad work
inand and if it takes a village to raise
a child you rais a young man our father
to be inspiration to all of us his
actions his acts his work um thank you
for remembering our
father if his
legacy he would say it's not so much in
the
works it's in his children and his
grandchildren and other childrens of the
city of Cleveland East Cleveland and
Cleveland Height University
Heights say thank you we thank thank you
um Reverend Moss thank
you thank
you with much respect and again
congratulations to the
family our next inductee is someone who
is well known inside and outside of this
room another great Community leader
Erica pisar
to introduce Miss pisar as estonia's
ambassador to the United States Mr
chrisan
PRI Ambassador PRI performed his
required military service in the
Estonian Defense Forces where he remains
a Reserve officer he's been decorated
with the order of the White Star by the
president of the Republic of Estonia the
cross of Merit of the ministry of
defense of Estonia as well as other
decorations he told us a few minutes ago
this is his second time to Cleveland
right he likes Cleveland so much he
would love to bring his family back for
a visit please welcome to the podium
Ambassador chrisan prick
[Applause]
thank you Russ thank you so much it's uh
quite an honor to be here
today and uh and I'd like to uh to thank
the Cleveland International Hall of Fame
and for uh uh for this kind
invitation and uh the moment I I got
this in
invitation few months ago
I told my my my staff my people my
team I got to
go for two
reasons firstly Russ as you said that's
my second time in in
Cleveland in
fact 24 years ago it was my my very
first trip to America and Cleveland was
one of the the very first cities that I
visited in America and whereas America
in general you know United States in
general is diverse International Place
Cleveland was certainly one of these
cities where I felt that it was not only
internationally uh diverse it was not
only proud about its diversity but it
was one of the these cities that really
embraced the international diversity
that embraced all the good that comes
out out of diversities I remember the
Greek festival that we attended here
just out of blue because we had we
because we had a Greek gentleman in our
group and I remember the uh the the
cultural Gardens that that I visited and
that left me uh an incredible impression
so the international diversity is is all
that this is this event is is all about
and you know I actually had a 74 minutes
speech I I clopped it but then then
council member POC uh reminded us to be
mindful of the time so I just have to uh
uh say very few few
notes the uh I am I'm deeply happy and
that's the that's the second and that's
the most important point where why I
told my team that I have to come here
I'm deeply happy that the Cleveland
International Hall of Fame has decided
to to honor one of my own of our own
Estonian Mrs Eric K
to to be the
inductee this this year Estonia is a
small country there are many small
country in the world Estonia According
to some stand standards maybe call a
tiny country even though my my my great
colleagues one of one of them is here uh
tells me that I I should never say that
I should only say that Estonia is a
compact country so Estonia is a Estonia
is a compact country of 1.3 million
people and so to to have have someone
who's who's left a mark in a huge
country in this Melting Pot part of
Nations United States of America it's
incredible Erica's
story is unique absolutely unique no
question about that but but I would also
say that her story is in a way typical
to to to the experience of so many
estonians of the 20th
century so she she was born in
Estonia but was forced to leave as a
toddler together with her family to flee
from the Soviet occupation and the and
the uh second world war to to
unknown I was really happy to have the
opportunity to actually also uh meet her
sister Silva and uh her
brother Axel together with with with
with you left left your home country and
in
1951 so several years later they left
Estonia several years that after they
they spent many years in U uh uh in
Germany in U uh camp for uh uh for
displaced people several years of living
the life of who knows what comes next
they made it uh to America first to
Michigan and uh Erica got uh his high
school diploma got her uh uh college
degree in Michigan but then moved here
to
Ohio where she's been ever since she's
been a
loved
educator you know educ education that's
great I I would spend another 74 minutes
by uh talking about that my own wife is
an educator so I'm very passionate about
that again she's she spent as an
educator for 30
years but but
very importantly in addition to all the
professional work or in addition to uh
to the paid work she
never failed to
to be an Estonian to be just a great
human being and to to introduce my
country her country our country to other
people in this room and and well well
well well beyond and I guess this this
is what what the this great fabric of
society this great fabric of U of
uh human coexistence is all about we we
tell stories about our countries we tell
tell tell uh listen to to the stories of
other
countries and then we we get richer and
richer uh by doing that every day Erica
has done this incredibly well she's been
one of those who has been developing the
the this whole project great project of
cultural Gardens her her roles invol uh
include the president of Estonian
cultural Garden the vice president of uh
of uh uh Cleveland cultural Gardens also
the vice president of uh of uh great uh
of the uh Baltic
uh Baltic Society whatever Baltic
Society of great Greater Cleveland and
many others and I guess through the all
these different roles again she's been
part of this great human fabric of
greater greater Cleveland
so before I
induct Erica I just have a pro proof
that I've been here this photo of myself
it was very dearly in my own private
archive from uh from May uh 26 of 2000
when I first uh came here and when I was
so impressed I was blown away by seeing
uh the Estonian cultural Garden in the
middle of American Heartland in middle
middle of Cleveland so thank you Erica
for this gift and thank you every
everyone who's been involved with with
Cleveland
U International Hall of Fame and
certainly to everyone who's been
involved with the cultural Gardens of of
of Cleveland this is a great project
that I hope many other cities and
countries will follow
[Music]
[Applause]
thank
you one more
thank you Ambassador brick for your kind
words of
introduction I greatly appreciate the
Cleveland International Hall of Fame for
this great
honor also the work of Debbie and Dan
Hansen is greatly appreciated it for
organizing this annual event it takes
almost a year to organize this so they
have worked long and hard thank
you I wish to introduce four special
members of my family who have traveled
long distances to witness this event if
they didn't witness it they wouldn't
believe but here I am
first of all my precious sister Silva
kikut
Bu
from Silva stand up from an Arbor
[Applause]
Michigan my my precious brother oxy
guch uh who came from
[Music]
who came and his wife reenie who C
traveled from Manhattan Beach
California and my two
precious
grandchildren Emmy Sam p and
Emmy and there are two large Circle
circular tables of people who have
supported me all these
[Applause]
years there
are three
countries
Estonia lvia and
Lithuania who are frequently called the
Baltic
states in the past the Cleveland Inter
National Hall of Fame they have inducted
they have inducted into the Hall of Fame
Ina where are you Ina buis from
Lithuania and from
Lille and this is my good fortune to be
inducted as the third member of the
Baltic
countries although born in three three
different countries we have many similar
attributes excuse me move it over a
little bit
sorry all three of us have common
attributes number one we were born in
our homeland of Estonia lvia and
Lithuania number two our families
escaped our respected countries in fear
of communist
rule number three we lived in DP camps
for several years in
Germany we immigrated to America in the
1950s we were educated in
America we are
mothers all and most of all all three of
us have been married to our spouse
for over 50
years remarkably all three of us made
time to take an active interest in our
homeland now you may ad
address where's
ing Anda and Erica
as the three Baltic
sisters I wish to relate a humorous
story a boy named
Jose was from Mexico and he was invited
to his first football game at
Progressive
Field when he returned turned from the
event his mother anxiously asked Jose
how did you like the
game Jose
replied it was great when I got to my
seat everybody in the stadium stood up
and sang Jose can you see
many of you have precious immigrant
stories my most memorable story is about
Mimi whose family escaped Vietnam as
vote
people Mimi was my first grades student
on her first day of school in America
the students had their usual lunch and
then went outside for
recess the school
playground it was surrounded by high
tennis uh
fence
when rea's was
over the playground
lady
blew blew her whistle all the students
were running Helter
Skelter to their assigned
stations however Mimi was confused and
seemed and sense imminent
danger she climbed the tall fence her
little feet were in the little
[Music]
sections she climbed the tall fence to
escape harm the playground lady was
horrified and yanked Mimi off the high
fence and escorted Mimi back to my
classroom Mimi was trembling with fear
and her face showed
Unforgettable
panic I tried to comfort her and explain
the
situation no one except Mimi understands
the perils that her family
endured perhaps this current situation
brought back horrible
memories I have sadly lost contact with
Mimi
I pray that she is
happy that she is safe in
America that she has high
selfesteem and that she became a teacher
just like her father was in
Vietnam my closing point is National and
anthems when we hear our
native
anthems it stirs our hearts and and
brings back
Nostalgia America has been good to us
for the most
part so when we hear the American
national anthem the last lines should
have special meaning
to us it
states oh
say does that Star Spangled Banner
wave over the land of the
free and the home of the brave thank you
[Applause]
Miss whar congratulations to you and I
could have used that whistle earlier
thanks our final inductee tonight is a
true Renaissance Man Mr Johnny Woo
Johnny will be inducted by Margaret
wall more than 50 years ago
award-winning practicing immigration
lawyer Margaret Wong began her firm
after years of adversity she was born in
Hong Kong and founded Margaret W Wong
and Associates LLC which began with a
single desk rented for $25 and is now
one of the nation's Premier immigration
law firms with offices in nine cities
she's an immigrant a selfstarter and a
proud businesswoman ladies and Gentlemen
please welcome to the podium is
maret yeah we all age so well here and
thank you thank you thank you Dan and
Debbie only you can bring us all
together for all of us who are not
prophit here is one of the richest men
in Cleveland Eddie Crawford where oh he
left he left with the Irish how could
yeah he's he's around here but there's
all the other people here here's one I
want to point out all the rich people
Veronica you and I will have to get them
to get us money to do stuff you know
that but thank you I don't mean to be
rude and thank you so much pad the
mother and Johnny uh Johnny I need you
up here my job is to introduce you I'm
so proud of my young friend he's awesome
he speaks Spanish he speaks Chinese of
course he's great in English and I knew
him when he was so young and both of us
were not wealthy not known but but here
we are and thank you and thank you so
much for coming we have grown up a lot
together um a lot of us were poor at one
time and now we're here and it's nice to
be able to have a nice dinner see old
friends get see each other get
recognized even though it's a Cinderella
for a few hours but that's great
John thank you Mr Johnny
wo last but not least
[Applause]
more thank
you so before I start um I'm going to
take a picture you guys with my crazy
gig Tier gear I have in my chest which
is a i
pen not working
is trying to take so it's unfortunately
it's not going to work right now so
anyway um thank you again for this
opportunity this honor I'm very blessed
to be here with all you guys um thank
you Dan Debbie and everybody in the
committee I just have a very very short
story since I'm the last one based on my
last name we're going to get this done
really really fast as we can go home
right it's it's past my bedtime anyway
the little story is 13 years ago Dan and
debie um started this
organization and every time he see me he
would say oh man Johnny you got
nominated you got nominated but you're
too young to get
in so 13 years later 14 years now
actually I finally sit in a big
table I really appreciate everyone for
being here it's very important to be who
you are and promote diversity as a whole
and again thank you that's it
have good
night Johnny
congratulations see at Lewa next week
it's a deal Dan you have some closing
thoughts
well I'll tell you if you weren't
inspired by that I I apologize for the
sound I guess some speakers are out and
it's kind of Muddy and all but you got
the gist please read about them in their
book read about them on the web page
because they're six incredible people I
think you got a taste of that tonight um
you can see the sponsors and all they've
been up there so I'm not going to read
them again but I do want to thank Russ
Mitchell he came in he did an amazing
job some of these names aren't Easy Ear
Russ he's a pro Pro and if you can join
me up here A second we always end the
Hall of Fame two ways we have a toast
and then we have the inductees come up
here the class photo maybe over here
we'll set up it's very important because
you see we keep it in the book we'll
have it in the museum and all that so
Russ come on up everyone raise a
glass and we're going to toast uh
Dona and
Veronica and Dr Jordan and and Erica and
Johnny and who am I missing at
Ambassador Ed so whatever language you
say I'm going to say slanta but here's
to you the class of
2024 thank you Russ thank you Pros Pro
want say good night Dan thank you so
much and once again thank you and Debbie
for inviting me here tonight hope you
had a great time once again congrats to
all the induct these tonight we will see
you next year safe travels home
[Music]